Wan-Lin CHAI

Mobile: +65 9658 6305

Email: <a href="mailto:chaiwanlin@u.nus.edu">chaiwanlin@u.nus.edu</a>
GitHub: <a href="mailto:chaiwanlin.github.io/">chaiwanlin.github.io/</a>

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/chai-wan-lin/

## **Personal Statement**

## Internship Objectives

I seek an internship role with an exciting entrepreneurial experience focused on software engineering or research, where creativity and analytics, in addition to critical thinking and communication skills, are essential towards achieving success.

### About Me

I am a second year undergraduate at the National University of Singapore studying Computer Science with Minor in Mathematics. I am writing to apply for this position as I am extremely keen to experience, learn and innovate at your company.

Growing up, science and technology has always intrigued me. The idea and beauty behind solutions designed by humans to solve our problems fascinates me. To quote Teddy Roosevelt: "Far and away the best prize that life offers is the chance to work hard at work worth doing", and work worth doing to me is to revolutionize and apply technology, particularly in the area of artificial intelligence (AI), to improve lives. Problems and challenges fuel me and I live for the excitement it brings me when I solve them or even when discussing and working on it.

### Strengths & Weaknesses

I thrive on great challenges and I am relentless in pursuit of solutions and answers to problems. I can pick up new skills and concepts quickly and apply them effectively.

However, overthinking and excessive deliberation occasionally impairs my judgement and efficiency.

## Work Experience

I have had first-hand experience in a co-living start-up as a Sales and Marketing intern just before their Series A, which raised US\$4.6million, where my role was extremely impactful to meet their target occupancy rate which was critical to their success.

Subsequently, I co-founded an e-commerce company in 2020 focused on alcoholic beverages after noticing its emerging demand in a small market. We have a lifetime revenue of USD\$180,000 while maintaining a good profit margin of 17.8% due to the high efficiency of our operations which is only possible from my implementation of existing technologies.

## How I can contribute to your company

With my exceptional passion in the field of computer science (especially in AI and machine learning), as well as my problem-solving skills, creativity and qualifications I am confident that I will positively contribute to your company.

Thank you for taking the time to review my application and I would greatly appreciate an interview opportunity to discuss my suitability for the position further.

_						
_	М		~		$\sim$	n
ᆫ	u	u	ca	ш	u	ш

Education		
Aug 2020 - Present	National University of Singapore Bachelor of Computing (Honors) in Computer Science with Minor in Mathematics • Specialization in AI (Course details in Appendix A)	Singapore
Jan 2016 - Dec 2017	<ul> <li>Raffles Institution</li> <li>Singapore-Cambridge General Certificate of Education Advanced Level</li> <li>Subjects: Biology (A), Chemistry (A), Mathematics (A), Economics (B)</li> </ul>	Singapore
Feb 2016 - Jan 2017	<ul> <li>E W Barker Institute of Sports (EWBIS)</li> <li>Studied with renown sports science institutions in New Zealand such as AUT Millennium and Massey University</li> <li>Led research on the impact of listening to music on athletic performance</li> <li>Presented research for EWBIS Symposium 2017</li> </ul>	Singapore, New Zealand
Work Experience		
Jul 2020 - Present	<ul> <li>Guzzlers Limited Liability Partnership Co-founder</li> <li>Lifetime revenue of USD\$180,000 with 17.8% profit margin</li> <li>Automated data processing for financial accounting and inventory tracking</li> <li>Designed and formatted company reports using Google Data Studio</li> <li>Designed and launched e-commerce website</li> <li>Developed and implemented Standard Operating Procedure (SOP) and sales funnel</li> </ul>	Singapore
Dec 2019 - Jun 2020  Scholastic Achievem	Cove Living Private Limited Sales & Marketing Intern  Responsible for nurturing and securing clients to meet target occupancy rate as well as managing digital collaterals used for marketing  Secured over 60 room bookings over course of 6 months to achieve over 90% occupancy rate  Optimized and automated internal processes to improve team efficiency  Designed and formatted sales reports with from company data using Google Data Studio	Singapore
Ocholastic Achievem	CHO/EXTROGITIONAL ACTIVITIES	
Jan 2016 - Dec 2017	<ul> <li>Raffles Institution</li> <li>Bronze medal for Asian Varsity Fencing Championship 2016</li> <li>2 bronze medals for Novices Fencing Championship 2017</li> </ul>	Singapore
Mar 2016 - Mar 2017	<ul> <li>Nurture Program</li> <li>Led community program under Central Singapore Community Development (CDC) to tutor underprivileged children</li> </ul>	Singapore

## Skill Sets & Proficiency

**Programming** Python Proficient

Java **Proficient** С Intermediate JavaScript Intermediate

**Shell Scripting** Basic

AI/ML Keras **Basic** 

TensorFlow **Basic** 

Web HTML, CSS Intermediate

Intermediate Django

**Database** SQL Intermediate

**Operating Systems** Linux Basic

Unix **Basic** 

Office Productivity Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel **Proficient** 

Multimedia Adobe Photoshop CS2 Intermediate

Non-technical Skills **Project Management** Basic

Writing/Publications **Basic** 

# Language Proficiency

**Spoken** English - fluent; Mandarin - fluent

Written English - competent; Chinese - average

## **Additional Information**

**Interests** Artificial general intelligence

Neural networks

Brain-machine interfaces Agriculture technology

Volleyball Fencing Photography

Poker

Degree: Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science

Cumulative Average Point: 4.43 / 5.00

Year	Level	Course Description	Grades
Aug – Nov 2020	Year 1/Semester 1	Programming Methodology	A
		Discrete Structures	B+
		Ethics in Computing	A+
		Linear Algebra	S
Jan - May 2021	Year 1/Semester 2	Data Structures and Algorithms	B+
		Programming Methodology II	A-
		Calculus for Computing	A
		Quantitative Reasoning	A-
Aug – Nov 2021	Year 2/Semester 1	Independent Software Development Project*	CS
		Software Engineering**	В
		Design and Analysis of Algorithms	A-
		Computer Organization	B+
		Probability and Statistics	B+
Jan – May 2022	Year 2/Semester 2	Intro to Artificial Intelligence	In-progress
		Machine Learning	In-progress
		Operating Systems	In-progress
		Linear and Network Optimization	In-progress

<sup>\*</sup> The **Independent Software Development Project** focused on designing and implementing a web application called Ticks Up to introduce simple option strategies to beginner investors. Ticks Up recommends optimized option strategies based on a user's sentiment of a stock, analyzes a user's portfolio diversity as well as track their portfolio performance. The project was written in Python on the Django framework then deployed on Heroku with a PostgreSQL database and used Selenium to scrape data required. The project was done in a team of 2 people.

### **NUS Grading Scale:**

A+ & A (5.0); A- (4.5); B+ (4.0); B (3.5); B- (3.0); C+ (2.5); C (2.0); D+ (1.5); D (1.0); F (0)

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn

<sup>\*\*</sup> The **Software Engineering Project** focuses on designing and implementing a Command Line Interface (CLI) desktop application, EdRecord, for teaching staff to easily monitor their students. EdRecord allows quick access and updates to student information (including assignment/attendance tracking as well as grading). The project is written in Java (with JavaFX, Jackson and JUnit5 libraries) and done in a team of 5 people.